DEVIN BLANKENSHIP

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

DETAILS

PHONE

2603486951

EMAIL

frontdevdevin@gmail.com

LINKS

Portfolio

<u>LinkedIn</u>

<u>Github</u>

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

HTML & CSS

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

JavaScript

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

React

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

Java

• • 0 0 0

SQL

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

Wordpress

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

Pega

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

Git

• • • • 0

Postman

• • 0 0 0

Visual Studio Code

 \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ

PROFILE

Hardworking and self-motivated programmer with 3+ years experience, looking to get back into Front End Development. I have experience with CSS, Javascript, and React. I like to keep up on new tools and technology by browsing Medium.com, checking r/Frontend subreddit and checking out new videos on Youtube and Udemy. Currently working on a React project using Google Firebase, and am implementing Hooks. Looking into Next.js and spending free time on CodeWars.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Software Engineer, Charles Schwab

Phoenix

Jan 2019 — Jan 2021

- Learned to work with the Pega application and make changes to Wire Transfers.
- · Made implementation changes to Mutual Fund flow.
- Worked with other departments to pull data form their API to create a new Account Open work flow. Created documentation for the API for better readability and understanding.
- · Used Parasoft Virtualize to create sample data to test our Account Open.
- · Debugged code using Pega's internal debugger as well as Splunk.

Web Developer, Collective Alternative

Indianapolis

Jul 2017 — Feb 2018

- Worked with account manager, creative director and content team to ensure website fits clients needs, as well as work on SEO and google analytics to optimize site.
- Launched websites and ran maintenance tests as well as Hosting and Domain Migration

EDUCATION

Front End Engineer, The Iron Yard

Indianapolis

Jan 2017 — Apr 2017

- Worked closely with other students to complete daily homework. Paired programming at times. Several group projects.
- Started from the basics of HTML/CSS and worked out way to React/Node.js periodically working with the back-end students (Ruby on Rails) on projects.

Full Stack Engineer, FDMGroup

Reston

Jun 2018 — Sep 2018

- · Classes covered SQL, Unix, Java, Sprint, JUnit, as well as a handle of others.
- Worked on a document uploader group project that hit key requirements set by instructor

Army Basic Training - National Guard - Infantryman

Multiple

Dec 2008 — Dec 2014